▍2026 WTA500 新加坡 女单第一轮
王欣瑜 6-1 6-2 维基奇 · 赛后转播商专访
Hi Xinyu, congratulations on the win.
欣瑜 恭喜你赢球
I think earlier on you expressed,
我记得你之前说过
obviously some respect for your opponent.
你很尊重这位对手
She's a good opponent,
她是个很好的对手
but the score was 6-1, 6-2.
但比分是 6-1 6-2
You must be,
你一定
very happy with the outcome.
对这个结果很满意吧
Yeah, I mean,
嗯 是这样
we've played once in Cincinnati this year
今年我们在辛辛那提交过手
and it was a tough tough match out there.
那一场打得非常非常艰苦
And I know she can play unbelievable
我知道她能打得极具侵略性
aggressive and I know she can
也知道她
hit some amazing winners,
能打出惊人的制胜分
but today I think I'm really happy
但今天我真的很满意
with the level
自己的水准
that I showed from the beginning
从这场球一开始
of the match until the end.
到结束都保持住了
And I think it was I would say it
我会说这
was very clean match and
是一场很干净的比赛
because I really served well, returned well
因为我发球好 接发也好
and I took the time away from her.
而且我压缩了她的时间
So yeah, it was a really good match.
所以这场球真的不错
You're right.
确实如此
Right from the start,
从一开始
you did look like you were very calm.
你看上去就非常沉稳
You had strong serve, delicate
发球很有威力 触球
when you touched and
又很细腻
that must have put you
这一定让你
in a very good head space already
很早就进入了很好的状态
from the getgo.
一上来就是
I would say it's the the work I put
我想这是我下的功夫
in like not just for this tournament,
不只是为了这一站
you know, it's it's something
而是
that I've been doing throughout the year
我这一年一直在做的事
and yeah, just working
就是一直在练
on taking the time away from my opponent
怎么压缩对手的时间
and maximise, you know,
还有就是
my aggressiveness on court.
把场上的侵略性发挥到最大
So I think
所以我想
from the beginning I was really sure
从一开始我就很清楚
of what I want to do on court like
自己在场上要做什么
not to just you know react
不是只做出反应
on the shots she gave me.
去接她打过来的球
Instead I was really trying
而是真的在努力
to compose my game.
把自己的节奏组织起来
Yeah.
是的
Yeah. It seemed like you
看起来你
were obviously serving well,
发球确实很好
finding your spots well, but also especially I
落点也找得很准
think returning really well.
但我觉得接发尤其好
like it seems like you're reading
看上去你能读出
her her serve and and not giving her time
她的发球 完全不给她时间
at all.
一点都不给
Yeah, I mean she's a big server,
是的 她发球很强
you know, you know that.
这个大家都知道
And I also I think
另外我想
because I know for me it's always important
对我来说一直很重要
to attack their second serves.
就是去攻击对手的二发
And I guess I kind of put pressure
我想我就是这样
on her in that way
给了她压力
so that you know maybe she's putting one
也许她的一发
or two less first serve
就少进了一两个
in and then you know I I took the chance
然后我抓住了机会
and then I got one or two breaks in the end.
最后拿到了一两个破发
Yeah.
是的
Now you seem very comfortable
你现在看起来很放松
and I'm wondering if if that's
我在想这是不是
because you just like Singapore.
因为你就是喜欢新加坡
You were here last year already
去年你就来过
and you did pretty well.
而且打得相当不错
Yeah, definitely.
是的 确实
I I made it to the semi-final last time
上次我打进了半决赛
and for to the doubles final
双打还进了决赛
and it's just the the crowd here,
而且这里的观众
they are they're amazing.
他们真的很棒
They're so cute. Like there is one lady,
特别可爱 有一位女士
she keeps coming
她一直来
to my match like not only in Singapore,
看我的比赛 不只在新加坡
but I kept seeing her around the world
我在世界各地都遇到她
and she goes like I mean that's so cute
她就这样 真的太可爱了
and I'm just Yeah.
我就是
really happy to be back here.
真的很高兴能回到这里
You know who she is?
你知道她是谁吗？
Yes. I mean not not like no no but I know
算知道 也不算 但我知道
because I think she knows one
因为她认识
of my friend because my friend she used
我的一个朋友 我那个朋友
to live in Singapore
以前住在新加坡
and then you know they know each other.
她们俩就这么认识了
Okay. Up next you're going to be playing
好 下一轮你要对上
against Joanna Garland.
葛蓝乔安娜
Is she an opponent you're familiar with?
这个对手你熟悉吗？
Oh okay. yeah I mean I
嗯 是这样
we played juniors together
我们青少年时期交过手
but yeah we didn't play each other
但那之后
after that a lot.
就没怎么再碰过
And I know
我知道
that she she was in the final
她打进过决赛
of that One Point Slam earlier in the year,
就是年初那个一分制表演赛
but yeah,
不过
I mean I would try to focus on on my game
我会专注在自己的比赛上
and try to play as aggressive as I did today
争取打得像今天一样有侵略性
and you know no matter what
不管
the results going to be, I know
结果如何 我知道
that I'm going to enjoy my match here.
我会享受在这里的比赛
Great.
很好
Do you have a favorite thing
有没有什么是你
about Singapore from last time
上次来新加坡
that you get?
最喜欢的？
I think it's the the multicultural
我想是这里的多元文化
because you know here they have lot
因为这里有很多
of Chinese and also especially they have lot
华人 尤其是有很多
of people from Guangdong or Hokkien
广东和福建来的人
and I'm from Shenzhen.
而我来自深圳
So that's in that case it's very similar.
所以感觉非常相似
So yeah it's kind of like home for me
对我来说这里有点像家
to be here.
待在这里
So I'm really happy.
所以我真的很开心
Okay.
好
So thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you guys for everything.
谢谢 谢谢大家为我做的一切